# Jacob Madsen

## **Managing Consultant**

1000 E 5th, Apt 536 Austin, Texas 78702 703-615-8987 jmmadsen16@gmail.com <u>Website</u>

## Summary

Experienced consultant with a demonstrated history of working in the software implementation, analytics, and digital services industry. Possesses a skilled technical background, in addition to management experience leading developers and proposal efforts for various Federal clients. My website (linked above) contains more details on my experience, skillset, and GitHub repositories.

#### Skills

### **Expertise:**

Full Stack (React, Node.js), Cloud (AWS, IBM), NoSQL (ELK, Mongo), Docker, Git, Data Analytics

## Languages:

JavaScript, Python, SQL

## Experience

### **IBM** | Managing Consultant

December 2020-Present, Austin, Texas

- Lead a team of developers to create an analytics dashboard (React, Express.js, Postgresql, MongoDB) for a US Air Force solicitation, and deployed the containerized solution to AWS.
- Selected by practice to mentor and teach IBM non-college hires (Co-Op program) programming and consulting skills in order to upskill them for full-time employment within IBM.

#### **IBM** | Senior Consultant

July 2018- December 2020, Washington D.C

- Managed a team of 6 front-end developers to create an analytics dashboard for USPS
   International Operations. This UI integrated with their Blockchain prototype to track and visualize millions of international shipments, allowing new visibility to their supply chain.
- Regularly author multiple RFI and RFP responses for Federal clients, designing and architecting solutions tailored to clients' needs while utilizing the latest cloud-native development principles.
- AWS integration lead for a General Services Administration project. Designed the architecture, provisioned AWS services, and worked with development leads to deploy the solution.
- Led internal practice effort to design strategies and blueprint repositories for creating user interfaces (React & ELK Stack), having identified skill gap when responding to proposals.
- Designed and deployed various microserviced applications for the Department of Veterans Affairs to authenticate users, monitor application health, and integrated with their ELK stack.
- Refactored an AI chatbot for the Department of Commerce from a monolith to a containerized, cloud-native solution, giving them flexibility for scaling and deployment in the cloud.

## **IBM** | Consultant

August 2016 - July 2018, Washington DC

• Consulted with the Ohio DoT to implement a PeopleSoft ERP. Participated in the entire SDLC from requirements gathering and design phases to SIT and UAT testing, and through hypercare.

## **Education**

University of Virginia | Bachelor of Arts - Economics / Business Leadership

August 2012 - May 2016, Charlottesville, VA